Tel: 408-874-5253 | Sacramento, CA

Accomplished creative and proficient Web/Front End with 5+ years of experience. With an eye for detail and a passion for creativity, I am confident that I can exceed expectations in Web design/ Front End.

- Loves to investigate technical challenges and look for solutions.
- Passionate about learning new technologies and create a knowledge base for providing innovative solutions.
- Possess excellent communication and interpersonal skills.
- Good Knowledge in Bootstrap and Responsive Web Design.
- Solid understanding of Document Object Model (DOM) and DOM functions.
- Ability to learn and adapt quickly to the emerging technologies.
- Experience in CSS3 properties for gradient, border radius, and animation etc.
- Expert in Debugging issues using Firebug/Developer Tool.

Qualifications

- Diploma in Multimedia Design and Development. (Humber College, 2013)
- Diploma in Art and Design Fundamentals.
 (Cambrian College, 2011)
 B.sc in Information Technology
 (Punjab Technical University)

Development Skills

- CSS3
- Java Script
- WordPress
- CMS
- HTML5
- Bootstrap 3
- React.js

Software Skills

- Adobe Photoshop CS6
- Adobe Dreamweaver CS6
- Adobe Illustrator CS6
- Sublime Text
- GitHub
- MYSQL
- Wix
- Adobe Acrobat

Feb 2020 - Present

Work Experience:

Client: Freelance Projects Role: Front End/Designer

Responsibilities:

- Put CSS3 image galleries together for some client.
- Continued learning in areas such as UI and AWS Cloud

Client: Providr Inc, Toronto, Canada From August 2015 to Feb 2020

Role: Front End Developer

Responsibilities:

- Requirement Analysis and design in discussion with PM and business.
- Created wireframes, XHTML code and CSS that contributed to user-centered design (UCD) efforts for dozens of web pages.
- Contributed on creating web pages using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and JQUERY plugins.
- Solid experience with Responsive Web Design (RWD).
- Collaborated on mock-ups and prototypes using HTML5 and CSS3.
- Used Content Management system (CMS) for the dynamic configuration of the header and footer of the web application
- Resolving all the assigned defects and interacting with QA to resolve any issues.
- Used W3C CSS Validator to check the mark-up validity.
- Wrote and edited copy across multiple websites, which helped to maintain a consistent marketing message.

Environment: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3

Client: Prime Deals International Ltd, Surrey, Canada

July 2015 to August 2015

Role: Front End Developer

Responsibilities:

- Every day to deal with online sales.
- Created banners and icons for the Websites.
- Everyday listing for new products.
- Develop a range of new themes using Wix ecommerce software.
- Creating order sheets regarding online shipments.
- Applied industry best practices and standards when project requirements were lagging.
- Sharing the functional and technical knowledge to the team members.
- Participate actively in the deliverables prioritization meeting.

Environment: HTML, CSS, Photoshop, illustrator, CMS

Client: SharpSchool (Intrafinity), Toronto, Canada

June 2014 to June 2015.

Role: Front End Developer

Responsibilities:

- Assisting with the conceptualizing and execution of graphic design solutions for a wide variety of web projects targeted for K-12 schools and government sites.
- Interaction with senior staff and clients as required for parameter/objective clarification.
- Develop a range of web templates using the company's own CMS software.
- Develop and maintain a range of brands, newsletter, and marketing materials both print and online.
- Proficiency in implementing the design to meet web standards (W3C) and worked on various browsers for cross-browser implementation.
- Worked with the QA team to fix the bugs, test the load, and performance checking.
- Used GIT HUB for the code repository.
- Sharing the functional and technical knowledge to the team members.

Environment: HTML, JavaScript, CSS

Client: Theapplabb, Toronto, Canada

b, Toronto, Canada Dec 2013 to May 2014

Role: Front End Developer/ UI Design

Responsibilities:

- Created illustrations for Theapplabb website.
- Created banners for events.
- Created app icons and graphics for the apps.
- Created logos for the client website.
- Collection framework used to transfer objects between the different layers of the application.
- Actively involved in code review and bug fixing for improving the performance.
- Documented application for its functionality and its enhanced features.

Environment: Photoshop, illustrator, HTML, CSS